In this short video I'm going to
demonstrate how you can apply a
access control to a folder on your PC.
So the first thing I need to do is in session
four there is a document that you need to
download Which is called the assessment
workbook and this is separate to the actual
full unit 3 assessment This is a document
just specifically for this task and what this
will allow you to do is provide evidence in
the form of screenshots to show that you can
apply a control to a folder on your system.
So the first thing to do is download and
save that in a suitable location on your
computer and then you scroll down and read
the instructions which it's asking you to
implement the basic cyber security control and
which is restricting file access on your PC.
Now there's space for four screenshots.
Uh, you may take more, you may take
less, but as long as you've been evidence
that you've taken this, uh, applied the
control and you've got screenshots to show
that that's your evidence for that task.
So as you can see, what I have here
is I have a folder called confidential
and I want to restrict access.
So at the moment I can double
click on that and access that.
But what I want to do is I want to make sure
that only certain people can access that.
So what I need to do is if I right click on
that folder and from the drop down menu, if
I select properties, this then brings up the
Dialogue box that contains all the different
properties and what you can do with that folder.
And the one we're looking for is security.
So if I switch to the security tab and
then I take a screenshot of that, and
that would be the screenshot I would take
and place that here for screenshot one.
So as you can see, there's three users there
and I want to restrict access to this user here.
And at the moment, as you can see,
or it has permissions or that user
has permissions for everything.
So what I need to do is I need to select edit
so I can make changes to the permissions.
So I select edit.
I then select the user.
And again.
You could take another screenshot at this
point and paste that as screenshot 2.
So how do I restrict the editing?
So as you can see, all of these are now grayed
out and the deny boxes have become active.
So by limiting the accessibility,
I need to remove the read.
So deny them the ability to access that folder.
So I click the little check box there and
select apply and I get a warning message.
So that warning message is telling me that once
I've set that that overwrites or supersedes any
other Instructions or permissions that that person
has which I'm happy to do So again, I can take a
screenshot of that and that would be screenshot
3 and I'll just select yes I'll click OK and
then click OK on that and now when I try to open
that folder I'll get a message saying you don't
currently have permission to access this folder.
So again another screenshot
And that will be screenshot 4.
And that will be your evidence in relation to
applying that control, the Sabre security control.
So once you've done that, you can then go
down to question 2 and This question is asking
you to think about what you've done that
you're evaluating the control you've applied.
So why did you use that control?
Why is it suitable for the threat?
So again, it's an access issue.
So why is that the best tool to use to
limit access and an explanation why other
controls are not suitable for that threat.
Um, and if there's a reason to not
use this control at any time, so
when wouldn't you use that control?
So once you've answered that, if you just
check through, make sure your screenshots show
you applying the control, you've answered the
question, you've carried out a spell check
and proofread and you're happy, save this
document and then you can then submit that
along with your assessment as your evidence.